Personal Information

Address: 1599A 39th Street Los Alamos, NM 87544

Phone: +1 (920) 858-8783

Email: casey.alan.anderson@gmail.com

CASEY A. ANDERSON

https://www.linkedin.com/in/caseyalananderson

Work Information

Address: P.O. Box 1663

Los Alamos, NM 87545

Phone: +1 (505) 667-5968 Email: casey_a@lanl.gov

Executive Summary

Nuclear engineer and **physicist** with six years of experience involving scientific computing, critical thinking, and analytical problem solving. Proven as a leader in student organizations, active as a team member in diverse work environments, and effective at publishing and communicating results.

Professional Experience

Brent Budden

Put in a quote right here about my work, maybe from Brent Budden or Someone else Brent Budden

Put in a quote right here about my work, maybe from Brent Budden or Someone else Brent Budden

Eh, nmaybe another node or quote here

Los Alamos National Laboratory

Los Alamos, New Mexico

GRA/PM NEN-5, Systems Design & Analysis 2016-Present
GRA/PM W-13, Advanced Engineering Analysis 2011-2012
Intern XCP-3, Monte Carlo Codes 2010

- Developing benchmarks and publishing reports on newly implemented features in MCNP [Pubs: ??,??,??]
- Modeling detector system responses using MCNP, Django, HTML, Javascript, and Python
- Working with SQL databases, managing servers, and utilizing version control using Mercurial
- Assisted in the development and testing of multi-physics analysis by coupling radiation transport results in MCNP with finite-element analysis in Abaqus/CAE
- Developed unstructured mesh human phantoms for health physics applications with MCNP6 [Pub: ??]
- Developed a software visualization package for finite element geometries in MCNP simulations

Medical College of Wisconsin

Milwaukee, Wisconsin

Graduate Research Assistant Department of Biophysics 2012-2016

Biophysics Representative, IT Liason Graduate Student Council 2014-2016

- Patented a segmented reconstruction technique for artifact reduction in MRI [Pat: ??]
- · Collaborated with medical doctors and other clinical researchers to secure NIH grant funding
- Submitted abstracts and presented findings at various international conferences [Pubs: ??,??,??]
- Served on the Graduate Student Council as Biophysics representative and Information Technology liaison
- · Collaborated with faculty, staff, and medical students to address and improve graduate school IT needs

University of Wisconsin - Madison

Madison, Wisconsin

Student Research Assistant Department of Medical Physics 2008-2011
Chapter President American Nuclear Society 2010-2011

- · Assisted in research, modeling, and analysis of brachytherapy seed quality assurance methods
- Managed organizational duties, arranged speakers, conference travel, socials, workshops, and meetings
- · Mentored students in Science Olympiad, science fairs, and obtaining Boy Scout merit badges

Areas of Expertise

Physics/Engineering

- Nuclear Engineering
- Fourier Analysis
- Monte Carlo Methods
- Signal Processing
- Magnetic Resonance Imaging
- Regularization Methods
- Radiation Detectors
- Multi-physics coupling
- O Computer Aided Engineering
- Finite Element Analysis

Software

- MCNP
- Abaqus/CAE
- Linux
- Matplotlib
- Matlab
- MacOS
- Windows
- Microsoft Office
- Vislt
- $\circ \, RELAP$

Programming

- Python
- Bash
- LATEX
- Unit Testing
- Matlab
- Mercurial
- Git
- → C/C++ • Fortran
- Java

Other Skills

- Technical Writing
- Presentations
- Leadership
- Version Control
- File I/O
- Scripting
- Debugging
- Validation & Verification
- Server Management
- Server Hardare

Key (Skill Level)

• Expert • Intermediate ○ Beginner

Education

M. Sc, Biophysics, Medical College of Wisconsin, GPA: 3.80/4.0 MAY 2016

"Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping: Exploratory Development and Initiation of Processing Pipelines"

MAY 2011

M. Sc, Nuclear Engineering & Engineering Physics, University of Wisconsin - Madison, GPA: 3.44/4.0 B. Sc, Nuclear Engineering, University of Wisconsin - Madison, GPA:3.24/4.0

Publications & Presentations

- 1. ‡ Casey Anderson et al. "Neutron and Gamma Correlations using CGM in MCNP 6.2.0 (LA-UR-20353)". In: *Proceedings of the 27th American Nuclear Society Summer Meeting.* (San Fransisco, California). 2017, Link
- 2. § James Tutt and Gregg McKinney. "Speed and Memory Improvements to MCNP6 Delayed-Gamma Line Treatment (LA-UR-21050)". In: *Proceedings of the 27th American Nuclear Society Summer Meeting*. (San Fransisco, California). 2017
- 3. [‡] Casey Anderson et al. "Delta-ray production in MCNP6.2.0 (LA-UR-16-25402)". In: 24th Conference on Applications of Accelerators in Research and Industry. (Forth Worth, Texas). Nov. 2016, Link
- 4. [‡] James Tutt, Casey Anderson, and Gregg McKinney. "Background-Source Cosmic-Photon Elevation Scaling and Cosmic-Neutron/Photon Date Scaling in MCNP6 (LA-UR-16-24928)". In: 24th Conference on Applications of Accelerators in Research and Industry. (Forth Worth, Texas). Nov. 2016, Link
- 5. James Tutt, Casey Anderson, and Gregg McKinney. "Delayed-Gamma Energy Biasing with Exact Energy Sampling in MCNP6.2.0 (LA-UR-16-24057)". In: *Proceedings of the 26th American Nuclear Society Winter Meeting*. (Las Vegas, Nevada). Oct. 2016, Link
- 6. || Casey Anderson et al. "Volume-Paracellated Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping". In: *Proceedings of the International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 24th Conference.* (Singapore, Singapore). May 2016, Link
- 7. † Casey Anderson and Kevin Koch. "Volume-parcellated Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping of the Human Brain at 7T". in: 2015 Minnesota Workshop on High and Ultra-High Field Imaging. (Minneapolis, Minnesota). Oct. 2015, Link
- 8. Casey Anderson, Kimberley Pechman, and Kathleen Schmainda. "Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping to Assess Iron Levels in Rat Brain Tumors". In: *Proceedings of the International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 22nd Conference.* (Milan, Italy). May 2014, Link
- 9. [‡] Casey Anderson, Tim Goorley, and Karen Kelley. "Mesh Human Phantoms with MCNP (LA-UR-12-01307)". In: *2012 3DS Simulia Community Conferece Proceedings*. (Providence, Rhode Island). May 2012, pp. 556–568, Link

‡Presentation Included; §Presentation Only; || Magna Cum Laude

Patents

i. Kevin Koch and Casey Anderson. System and method for localized processing of quantitative susceptibility maps in magnetic resonance imaging. WO Patent App. PCT/US2016/038,723. Dec. 2016. URL: https://www.google.com/patents/W02016209930A1?cl=en, Link

Classes & Trainings

- I. "MCNP6 Intermediate Workshop", (Los Alamos New Mexico). May, 2016
- II. "CPR Certification Training", (Milwaukee, Wisconsin). May, 2015
- III. "General Electric MR Programming Workshop", (Madison, Wisconsin). Oct, 2014
- IV. "Dale Carnegie Training", (Los Alamos, New Mexico). August, 2011
- V. "Introduction to Abaqus", (Minneapolis, Minnesota). June, 2011
- VI. "Introduction to Python Programming", (Los Alamos, New Mexico). July, 2010
- VII. "MCNP5 Beginner Workshop", (Los Alamos, New Mexico). May, 2010